Is your definition of happiness
你觉得一个寿数不长
to be with a dying man
随时会陨命的人
who might leave her any second?
可以带给别人幸福吗
If he’s the only one
若海市想要的幸福
to make her happy,
就是这么一个人
then yes.
有何不可
Have you ever considered
清海公可曾想过
what she truly wants?
海市想要的是什么
You push her away
你也许因为寿数不长
because you might not live long,
不想耽误海市
but to her,
可对于海市而言
even if she could be with you
能跟相爱的人在一起
for only one day,
哪怕是一日
that’d be enough.
都是幸福的
Master.
师父
Here’s your medicine, Master.
师父 该喝药了
Not again!
又喝
I’m following
师父的身体啊
the physician’s instruction
需要细细调养
for the sake of your health.
这方面我只听医官的
No objection.
师父说什么都没用
Take this, Master.
师父 张嘴
I’m off.
我走了
Haishi,
海市
read this.
给你看一下
It appears to be Zhang Chengqian
张承谦只寄了封家书来
writing back and saying all is well.
家书上只报了平安
That’s it.
其他只字未提
He’s telling us
他的意思是
everything is fine at Huangquan Pass.
黄泉关如今风平浪静
After you asked me to keep an eye
可师父那时候交代我
on Tang Qianzi,
监视汤乾自
I did catch him gesturing
我确实看到汤乾自
to someone secretly,
与人打了手势
but I’ve yet to discover
只是我到现在都没查出
his contact.
汤乾自是与何人联系
He’s been with Lord Chang for years
汤乾自追随昶王多年
as his right-handed man.
也是昶王身边的近臣
Lord Chang
这昶王
has been indulging himself in pleasure
自打身体无碍以后
ever since he recovered.
日日声色犬马
He’s mysterious.
心思也是很难琢磨
You’re well aware of the situation.
既然你心里有数
And since
还有
Zhang Chengqian says
张承谦称
Huangquan Battalion is safe,
黄泉营眼下无事
you won’t be needed back there.
这段时间你不必回去
You mean I can stay in the capital?
师父要我留在都中
You don’t want to?
你不愿意
I’d love to!
我非常愿意
Do you still want me to keep this?
你觉得这个留着无用了
Thank you, Master.
谢谢师父
I know
我知道
you only let me go
师父每次让我走
for my safety.
都是因为担心我的安危
You mean to protect me.
不想让我出事
But
可是
in our line of duty,
我们做的事情
people could die any minute.
哪有长生的呢
Every time we parted,
每一次分开
it could be forever.
都不知能否再见面
So,
所以
I’m not afraid of death.
海市不怕危险
I’m afraid
海市只怕师父
that you push me away
不让我待在身边
or let me go.
只怕师父让我走
Haishi,
海市
I promise
你放心
I won’t let you go again.
我不会再让你走了
Your Majesty,
陛下
with autumn coming on,
今已入秋
defense around the capital and Mount Mingluo
京畿附近和铭泺山
has been reorganized
已按照部署
according to the plan.
重新布防
Especially Mount Mingluo in the north.
尤其是北边的铭泺山
The garrison there has been increased.
已加强了守卫兵力
I’ve read the report.
朕看过奏章
Good work.
切实可行
Is there anything else?
众卿可还有事要奏
Your Majesty,
陛下
Lord Chang has skipped morning court
昶王自上次受伤中毒
for days ever since he was poisoned.
已数日未曾上朝
Meanwhile, magicians
昶王府近日杂耍艺人
and foreign eagle egg sellers
和卖鹰隼蛋的外族人
are flocking into his mansion.
越来越多
They’re partying every night.
夜夜笙歌
I don’t think...
臣唯恐
Jichang was wounded and poisoned
季昶为了救朕
in order to save me.
受了伤 中了毒
End of discussion.
罢了
Yes, Your Majesty.
是 陛下
That’s all for today. Court adjourned.
既无他事 退朝
Court adjourned.
退朝
- Good day, Your Majesty.
恭送陛下
Look.
你看看
Isn’t it nice?
你看我这不错吧
It’s a real treasure,
这可真是好宝贝
am I right?
是不是啊
Of course.
是啊
It’s beautiful!
漂亮
Lord Chang is quite generous.
这昶王殿下还真是豪爽
Please.
请
You have a visitor, Lord Chang.
昶王殿下 客人到
You may leave.
退下吧
- Yes.
是
Let me see it.
让我瞧瞧货色
Glossy hair.
毛色还真光亮
Is this eagle the best of the best?
是一等一的好鹰隼吗
If not,
若不值这个价钱
I won’t
我可一个子儿
pay a dime.
也不会付的
Not bad.
不错
Nice hair.
毛也好
Sharp claws.
爪喙也锐利
If it catches the prey,
若是能一搏毕功
I’ll cash in
我便立即
on the agreement
兑现与你家王君
Lord of Left Pudun and I made.
左菩敦王当初议定之酬
Dazheng won’t get in your tribe’s way
贵部与迦满交战吞并
of conquering Jiaman.
大徵绝不干预
Your Highness,
殿下
help me! Please!
快 快救我
Your...
殿
Don’t!
不要
Your Highness!
淑容妃
I’m here, Your Highness!
奴婢在 奴婢在
did you have another bad dream?
可是又做噩梦了
Your Highness!
淑容妃
I saw assassins
我梦见
attacking His Majesty again.
又有人要对陛下不利
The assassination is over.
事情都已经过去了
All those spies and killers
细作和刺客
have been seized.
都已经擒拿了
His Majesty is safe.
陛下不会有事的
Your Highness,
淑容妃
I can go to Jincheng Palace
要不要奴婢去金城宫
to ask His Majesty over.
请陛下过来
His Majesty’s tied up with work lately.
陛下最近政务繁忙
Do not disturb him.
绝对不可以惊扰他
I’m fine.
我没事
I can handle
不就做了个噩梦嘛
a little night terror.
我缓缓就好了
His Majesty has arrived.
陛下驾到
Don’t move.
别起来了
You’re safe. I’m here.
没事了 朕来了
I’m with you.
朕来了
Evil spirits can’t hurt you.
邪魅魍魉就散了
Did you have a nightmare again?
又做噩梦了
It’s happening
你连番噩梦
because you’re too weak.
就是身子太虚了
I’ve called the physician.
朕已经宣了御医了
Your Majesty,
陛下
I’m used to it.
都是老毛病了
It’s nothing serious.
无妨的
It is serious
什么无妨
and should be treated
老毛病拖着
as soon as possible.
就成了大毛病了
Look at you
你看你
with pale lips and cold hands.
唇色发白 手又冰凉
Are you taking the medicine
你有没有按照
they prescribed?
他们开的方子吃药
And you!
还有你们
Can’t you see
淑容妃的身子
how sick she is?
都差成这样了
Why didn’t you report to me?
为何不告知朕
If anything happens to her,
她要是出了什么事
can you take the consequences?
你们谁担得起
She’s been like this
淑容妃一连几日
for days.
都是这样
I meant to ask you to come over
奴婢早想请陛下来的
but she said no.
可她不让
I stopped them.
是我不让她们去的
You’re too busy with work
陛下最近忙于政务
to be distracted.
我怕惊扰了您
Besides, I’m totally fine.
再说我真的没事
You should’ve let me know.
你这又是何苦呢
Come here.
来 快快快
Greetings, Your Majesty.
臣参见陛下
Have you looked closely
淑容妃的脉案
at Consort Shurong’s symptoms?
你们仔细看过了吗
What’s wrong with her?
究竟如何
Your Majesty,
回禀陛下
Consort Shurong is worried about your safety
陛下在帝姬府遇袭
due to the assassination at Princess’s Mansion,
淑容妃担忧陛下安危
causing the night terror and sweat
才致梦多盗汗
and the deterioration of her disease.
病情也有所加重
I’m safe and sound.
朕已经没事了
What’s more
你的心思又何必
to worry?
如此之重呢
Physician Li,
李御医
she’s been
淑容妃
taking medicine
已按照你们开的方子
that you prescribed.
在吃药
Why are her hands and feet still cold?
为何手脚还是冰凉
Why is she still so weak?
身子还是这么虚
Well...
这
Her cold
寒症
and blood stasis
血瘀
are...
难
are hard to be cured.
难以根治
That again?
又是难以根治
Useless!
朕要你何用
Cure her
你要是治不好淑容妃
or you’ll be dead!
朕要你的脑袋
Do it!
想
I... I’m sorry, Your Majesty.
陛下息 息怒
(Tianqi) Did Lord Qinghai
那日回去后
say anything when you got back that day?
清海公有没有
Master?
师父
Nothing really.
倒是没说什么
I can stay in the capital, though.
师父让我留在都中
I’m happy for you.
那就好
Since when
你何时与师父
did you two become so close?
变得如此熟了
That’s our secret.
秘密
Anyway,
不过此番
why are you
你也是太仓促了
rushing to Shangzhou?
就这么急着要到殇州去
They say that place is
我听说殇州苦寒萧瑟
even more desolate than Hanzhou
比瀚州更甚
and covered with snow.
而且是一片雪国
Why don’t you wait
你就算要去
until next spring?
也等来年春天再去啊
Rumor has it
听说雪山城
that a mysterious saber manual
出现一本神秘刀谱
of long-lost skills is in Xueshan.
上面所记都是失传绝学
I’m from a family of saber,
我家代传刀法
so I’d like to see for myself.
因此想去看看
When will you be back?
何时回来
I’m not sure.
还不知道
By the way,
对了
when I said
上次我说我要
I was going back to Huangquan Pass,
回黄泉关的时候
you told me
你对我说
you wished you’d have more time
本来有些事想做
to get something done.
只可惜来不及了
What was that?
是为何事
If you still have
如果在天启城中
unfinished business here,
还有未做完的事情
just leave that to me.
你可以托付给我
Why do you want to help?
为什么想要帮我
We’re friends.
我们是朋友啊
Right, friends.
朋友啊
I have nothing else to do.
我已经没什么事要做了
It’s no trouble at all.
你不用跟我客气的
Don’t get me wrong.
不是跟你客气
I didn’t realize until recently
是我前两日才知道
that it was already too late
我想做的事
for that matter.
已经来不及了
Young Master Zhou,
小侯爷
we’re ready to set off.
车马已备 应当启程了
Let’s go.
去吧
See you.
后会有期
Be careful. Slowly.
小心点 小心点
Don’t break anything.
千万别磕着碰着的
- Yes. - All this is for His Majesty
这是陛下和淑容妃
and Consort Shurong.
要用的
(Jincheng Palace) Don’t drop it
要是弄坏了
for your own sake.
仔细点你们的小命
Be careful.
小心点
- Eunuch Mu. - Yes.
穆内官
Mr. Fang Haishi.
小方大人
Push.
往里
What’s this?
这是
His Majesty and Consort Shurong
陛下让淑容妃
are going to the resort palace at Diequan Valley
到蝶泉谷行宫
for convalescence.
去疗养一段时日
We’re packing up.
让奴婢们正准备着呢
His Majesty is going out?
陛下要出宫了
Consort Shurong’s cold is lasting.
淑容妃的寒症久治不愈
Physicians say
御医说
the hot spring at Diequan Valley
蝶泉谷的温泉
has a significant effect on it,
对寒症颇有疗效
but it’s a lot less effective
可是要把温泉水
being carried all the way
全都运到城中来
to the city.
这疗效就损失了很多了
That’s why His Majesty has decided
陛下方才决定
to go there tomorrow
明日出宫到蝶泉谷行宫
for the sake of
让淑容妃
Consort Shurong.
在那儿疗养一段时日
I won’t take up any more of your time.
那穆内官你先忙
Good day.
我先告退了
Sure.
好
(Jincheng Palace) Nice and easy.
小心点 小心点
Be careful.
小心点
Do not...
千万
Do not drop it!
千万小心点
Master.
师父
Come in.
进来
I saw Eunuch Mu and his staff
我今日见到穆内官
packing things up
看到他正带着内官
earlier today.
在打点行装
He says His Majesty
他说陛下
is taking Consort Shurong
明日要带着淑容妃
to Diequan Valley tomorrow for her health.
前往蝶泉谷行宫修养
What do you think about that?
你以为如何
With the fake princess and her accomplices gone,
伪帝姬的事情刚刚平息
the capital seems peaceful again
天启城表面风平浪静
but danger might lurk under the water.
但难保不会有暗流涌动
I meant to talk His Majesty out of it,
我本想劝谏陛下
but it’s not my place to say so.
又觉得不合规矩
Are you going to talk to him, Master?
师父是否要劝谏陛下
I guess not.
也是
You know him more than anyone.
师父最了解陛下
He wouldn’t listen anyway.
想必也是劝不住的
Then let me
那师父尽管将保护陛下
protect him
与淑容妃的职责
and Consort Shurong.
交给海市
You’d better stay and rest, Master.
师父 您就好好养伤吧
Lord.
公爷
Master.
师父
Come in.
进来
Do you have the map of Diequan Valley?
蝶泉谷的地图带来了吗
Yes.
带来了
Let’s take a look.
一起来看
Diequan Valley has a rough terrain,
蝶泉谷地形错落
but by taking over the peak,
但只要稳据高处
every post
据点之间
can be alerted timely
便能及时以消息相接
to ensure safety of the resort palace.
行宫无碍
I’ve had troops placed on garrison
陛下下旨之后
right after His Majesty’s edict.
卓英已经派人布防
They should be in position
此时
by now.
应该已经一一布防好了
Shaozi,
哨子
what about Secret Force
途径的山林
along the way
还有蝶泉谷的周围
and around the Valley?
暗卫布防如何
They’ve scouted out the area
暗卫已经在蝶泉谷搜寻
and had men on patrol this whole time.
并安插值岗 至今未断
We have guards outside the Valley, too.
谷外 也安置了人手
If anything happens inside,
只要谷内一有动静
they’ll seal the Valley right away.
便能第一时间包围山谷
One squad to rescue. One to search.
一队救援 一队搜山
Haishi,
海市
you and Zhuoying
明日你跟卓英一起
will leave with His Majesty tomorrow.
跟随陛下的队伍出发
He and Consort Shurong’s safety
务必保证陛下
is a top priority.
还有淑容妃的安全
Yes, Master.
是 师父
Go get prepared.
各自准备
Get into it.
你先去泡吧
I’ll wait for you here.
朕在这儿候着
Your Majesty,
陛下
we failed
此番匆忙
to get everything ready
只有一日时间
in one day before the trip.
各事项都未打点妥当
Right now,
眼下
Master is checking the hall.
师父先去殿内打点了
It’s heavily guarded there.
考虑到陛下与淑容妃
I suggest
此时的安危
you and Her Highness rest inside first
并且那边守卫严谨
for your safety.
不如先去殿内歇息
I understand your concern,
道理朕都知道
but Consort Shurong is too weak
但淑容妃的身子
to wait any longer.
怕是不能再拖延了
Aren’t you here
你说的那些
to protect us?
不就是朕带你
Mr. Fang Haishi.
小方大人
Yes, Your Majesty.
臣在
You’re an excellent archer
小方大人箭术过人
who can hit the target from afar
百步之外可以穿杨
and shoot
行动之中
flying birds on the move.
可以射中天上的飞鸟
You even
一箭射中了
killed the former Lord of Left Pudun
鹄库的老左王
with an arrow,
让他毙命当场
which is unprecedented.
更是首功
I can’t take the credit for that.
臣不敢居功
You can only see far
既然箭术过人
to shoot far, I assume.
那目力也应该过人吧
Here comes your help.
你的救兵来了
Your Majesty.
陛下
Mr. Fang Haishi.
小方大人
Lord Qinghai,
清海公
His Majesty asks you to sit.
陛下赐座
Here’s your seat.
那椅子就摆放在这儿了
Sure.
好
Thank you, Eunuch Mu.
有劳穆内官
You’re welcome.
奴婢不敢
I serve at the pleasure.
清海公抬举奴婢了
Does Mr. Fang Haishi need...?
小方大人 这
He’s fine.
无妨
Lord Qinghai,
清海公
do you need any snacks, drinks
您看还有什么吃的用的
or other things?
需要的
Just let me know.
您跟奴婢说一下
I’ll bring them to you.
奴婢去给您准备一下
His Majesty asks me to oversee
陛下有旨监刑
the punishment. I should focus.
还是恭谨些比较好
Master...
师父
Don’t move.
跪好
Lord Qinghai,
清海公
Mr. Fang Haishi,
小方大人
it just occurred to me
奴婢突然想起来了
that I hadn’t got all fruits
前边还有一些瓜果吃食
and snacks ready out there.
没摆放好
I need to go check.
我得回去看一下
Please make yourselves at home.
二位请自便就好
Good day, gentlemen.
奴婢告退
I’m kneeling
师父坐椅子
while you’re sitting comfortably.
我跪蒲团
My knees hurt.
膝盖好疼
You’re lucky enough
没挨棍子
not to be flogged.
已经非常侥幸了
Your knees
眼睛不懂事
are taking the blame for your eyes.
膝盖可不得疼
Master,
师父
I meant to have you stay
我本想着师父
and rest at Zhaoming Palace
可以在昭明宫好生休养
instead of coming with me,
不想让师父跟来
but
不过
being with you
能像现在这样
here alone
跟师父两个人静处
isn’t half bad.
好像也挺好的
Be quiet and reflect on your mistake.
好好静思己过
Master,
师父
this place is the most vulnerable to attack,
此处布防最为松散
but His Majesty
陛下任性
insists on staying here.
不听劝谏
Eunuch Mu has left.
眼下穆内官也走了
There’s just the two of us.
没人看着我
Master, we can look around
师父 你若是不放心
in case there are loopholes.
咱们去四处查看一下
Master.
师父
Your Majesty!
陛下
Protect His Majesty!
护驾
Duohanersa!
夺罕尔萨
Your Majesty!
陛下
Haishi!
海市
Protect His Majesty!
保护陛下
Are you all right, Your Majesty?
陛下 你没事吧
Your Majesty!
陛下
Escort His Majesty back!
护驾回宫
Put His Majesty on the bed.
扶陛下到床榻
Your Majesty!
陛下
Your Highness,
淑容妃
His Majesty
陛下有伤
must be treated immediately.
需要即刻治疗
Please leave the room.
请您先回避一下
- Lord Qinghai... - Your Majesty.
清海公 陛下
Rest assured.
请您放心
I will
一有消息
keep you updated.
臣会立刻通知您
Shaozi,
哨子
step up security
增派人手
and escort Her Highness back.
送淑容妃回宫
Yes, Lord.
是 公爷
You saw that assassin’s face.
你见过那个刺客
Make sketches
立即画影图形
and seize him quickly.
尽快抓捕
Yes.
是
Go back with Shaozi
你跟哨子一起
to beef up security
回去增派人手
of the palace.
保证宫城的安全
But your wound, Master...
师父 你的伤
I’m fine.
放心
Focus!
都打起精神
Check everyone in and out carefully!
所有进出人等严加排查
No slacking!
不容有任何懈怠
Any negligence
如有遗疏
will lead to dire consequences!
严惩不贷
Double the guards.
加岗一倍
No slacking!
不得懈怠
Any negligence
如有疏漏
will lead to dire consequences!
严惩不贷
Lanterns on.
掌灯
Master.
师父
What do you think?
你看如何
Jincheng Palace is as bright as day.
这金城宫亮如白昼
Whoever tries to break in
不管什么人在此
won’t be able to
一切行止
hide their trace.
都无从遁形
Master...
师父
Go back to Zhaoming Palace first.
回昭明宫再说
Wind Waker...
召风师
is said
还以为像这样的人
to be extinct,
已不存在于世
but somehow,
没想到鹄库
Huku still has such a wizard.
还有这样的奇才
He recognized me
他已识破徒儿的身份
and called me “Duohanersa”.
唤我夺罕尔萨
I guess
这么多年
you can no longer keep my identity
您一直隐瞒徒儿的身份
a secret after all these years.
此番怕是瞒不住了
I assumed Secret Force
您之前派暗卫
watching Lord Chang’s Mansion
去监控昶王府
wouldn’t find
徒儿本以为
anything suspicious,
不会有任何收获
but just now, one of them reported...
但方才暗卫来报
Young Master Zhuoying,
大公子
I was searching for the suspect
属下拿着您分发下去的
according to your sketch
画像前去追查
and found a match
日前确有一名
who got in and out
形似画像上的人
of Lord Chang’s Mansion
曾去过昶王府
quickly the other day.
片刻即离
And there’s more than that.
而且还不止如此
What else?
还有什么
It’s confirmed
暗卫探知
that some magician
说之前
also went to
有演戏法的戏师
Lord Chang’s Mansion.
曾去过昶王府
Someone must’ve
只怕是
paid him first
对方收买的戏师先行
before that poisoned boy
而后才有那个
showed up
中了毒
who tried to kill you.
进而行刺您的小男孩
Master,
师父
we’re talking about a suspect
此事事关昶王
who’s His Majesty’s only brother.
他可是陛下唯一的弟弟
He also took the hit
之前我们在擒获
for His Majesty
伪帝姬时
when that fake princess attacked him.
昶王又舍身救下了陛下
We can’t go after him
若无确凿证据
without solid evidence.
实在不敢妄下结论
Besides,
另外徒儿认为
if he’s behind the assassination,
若此事真与昶王有关
he must be up to something even bigger.
背后可能
Have you considered
这么多年
going back to Hanzhou over the years?
有没有想过回瀚州
Going back there?
回瀚洲
Master,
师父
the day you saved me
自您救我那日起
is the day I put Hanzhou behind.
徒儿已不再想回瀚州
We people of Huku
我们鹄库男儿
are grateful
知恩图报
and loyal.
不移不易
You were shaved
还记得在红药原
when I first found you
捡到你的那日
at Red Plain.
你是个小光头
It’s probably your local custom
这可能是鹄库人的习俗
to remove children’s fetal hair
在生辰当日给剃了胎发
on their birthdays
被认可为
as a sign of being old enough for war.
可以上战场的男丁了
I don’t remember too much
生辰当日的事
about my birthday.
徒儿已经记不清楚了
Back then,
我还记得
I asked you about your name
我问你叫什么名字
and you said
然后你说了一句
some strange words
古怪的话
in an ancient dialect of Huku, I guess.
我猜是鹄库的古语吧
An ancient dialect of Huku?
鹄库古语
I have no memory of that at all.
徒儿现在真的不记得了
It was long.
一大串
Something starting with
我记得好像开头
“Zhuoying”.
你说了卓英二字
That’s why
所以后来
you were named after that.
就给你起了这个名字
Why are you bringing all this up?
师父今日真是稀奇
If I returned to Hanzhou,
我若回了瀚州
all that effort and time you spent on me
那师父这么多年的教导
would be in vain.
不就白费了
Don’t you hate
师父不是最不喜欢
futile effort the most?
那种徒劳无功的人吗
Legend has it
人说
that thousands of years ago on the northern grassland,
数千年前在北方草原上
there was a man named Sijiu
有一个叫寺九的人
who spent 12 years
为了驯服一匹龙裔天马
taming a Dragon-horse
用了十二年与之周旋
until his body turned stiff
直到身如石
and hair thin.
发如草
When he finally had a chance
终于有机会
to mount it,
骑到龙裔天马之上
that Dragon-horse neighed
天马嘶鸣
and galloped between heaven and earth
在天地间踏着虹霓云电
for 12 years.
奔驰十二年
And just like that,
就这样
Sijiu was on its back
寺九就在马上
the entire time.
一待就待了十二年
In the end, it was tamed
最后天马被驯服
and turned into a girl
化作女子
who then had four children with Sijiu.
与之生了四个孩子
The four of them
这四个孩子
were the founders of the four tribes of Huku
就是鹄库四部的祖先
and the chosen ones.
亦是龙孙
The first day I saw you,
从我第一日看到你开始
I instantly knew
我就知道
you were a war-horse.
你是一匹烈马
A war-horse
但是这么好的马
doesn’t belong to a pigsty
圈养于犬豕群中
by nature.
却是暴殄天物
I’ve been teaching you combat skills
我养育你这么多年
and strategies for so long
教你武功 教你经略
so that you can go out there
就是希望有一日
and make a difference someday.
可以看到你风驰电掣
Lift Hanzhou out of war.
让瀚州不要再腥风血雨
Stop further bloodshed.
人们不要互相残杀
But right now, you’re still in danger.
您身侧现在局势未明
Lord Chang could be the mastermind
现又有昶王有疑
and national security is at risk.
更牵扯到朝廷军政
I need to stay
徒儿愿留下
to share your burden.
为您分担一些
I want to keep you here
我也想你留在我身边
in the capital,
留在都中
but you have
可是有些事情
your own mission.
非你不可
Haishi is suspicious of your identity
自海市看到你哥哥之后
after seeing your elder brother.
对你的身世有所猜疑
And Wind Waker
更不用说
called you by your real name.
召风师说出你的名字
You can no longer
所以你一定不可以
stay here.
留在都中
But if you go back to Hanzhou,
若回瀚州
your tribesmen won’t trust you.
又会被同族猜忌
That leaves you
所以眼下
with only one option.
就只有一个办法
It’s all my fault. My bad.
都怪我
I should’ve stopped His Majesty
我不应允陛下
from going to Diequan Valley.
去蝶泉谷就好了
Calm down, Your Highness.
淑容妃别急
Bizi will bring back
碧紫姐姐前去打探了
information quickly.
很快就会回来了
What do you know?
怎么样
Guards at Yu’an Palace, Jincheng Palace
除了愈安宫 金城宫外
and the main gate
宫门口都比平时
are all doubled.
多了一倍的守卫
Long drum lanterns
金城宫内
have lit up the entire Jincheng Palace
点了无数的长鼓形灯
as if it’s in the daytime.
照得如同白昼
I also saw
奴婢还看见
Mr. Fang Haishi on patrol
小方大人他们
with the others
一直都在轮值
during the whole time.
寸步不离
How’s His Majesty?
那陛下身体呢
Physician Li is with him
李御医在金城宫内
at Jincheng Palace.
守着呢
I didn’t see others go in or out.
但是并没有其他人进出
His Majesty should be fine.
应该是无恙
That’s right, Your Highness.
是啊 淑容妃
If not,
若是陛下身体有恙
Imperial Hospital
医官院那边
would’ve made a fuss.
早就乱成团了
Dragon Tail,
龙尾神
please bless His Majesty.
保佑陛下平安无恙
Your Highness,
启禀淑容妃
Eunuch Mu is here.
穆内官来了
- Good evening, Your Highness. - Skip that.
参见淑容妃 免礼免礼
Is His Majesty all right?
陛下如何
He says
陛下说
don’t worry.
请淑容妃安心
So he’s fine, right?
陛下身体无恙
Just don’t worry.
总之请您安心便是
He...
那 那
Please excuse me.
奴婢告退
Thank you.
多谢内官
I’m glad he’s fine.
无事便好
Dragon Tail, please bless His Majesty.
请龙尾神保佑陛下
Please protect him from any harm.
保佑陛下安然无恙
Master,
师父
are you sure
您真的要让卓英
it’s the right thing to do?
这么做吗
Master, it’s me.
师父 是我
How is it going?
如何
Everything at Jincheng Palace
金城宫的一切安置
is all set
已按照师父的吩咐
as you requested.
布置妥当
I’m here to report back to you.
特来向师父复命
I see.
知道了
Do you need to see a physician?
需要我帮您请医官来吗
I’m good.
没事
Go back on patrol
你回金城宫巡视
in case assassins break in again.
以免有刺客再卷土重来
Are you sure you’re fine?
师父的身体当真没事
I just need some rest.
我只需要歇息而已
Jincheng Palace’s safety is all on you.
金城宫的安危就靠你了
Yes.
是
Master,
师父
if we keep this from Haishi,
如果这件事要瞒着海市
what if...?
我怕万一
This mission is putting your life
这事关你的生死
and career at risk.
还有你的前途
No one else should know.
只可你知我知
Your return to Hanzhou
这次你回瀚州
provides the best opportunity.
机会难得
Do not waste it.
千万不要大意错失
Your elder brother and uncle are against each other.
你哥还有你叔父
You can use that
这次回去
to your advantage.
正好有一番作为
I’ll have our men help you, too.
我也会派人襄助于你
Yes.
是
Don’t worry about Zheliu.
柘榴那边
I’ll keep an eye on her.
我会照顾她
She’ll be fine.
不会让她受委屈
I won’t let you down.
徒儿定不辱使命
You’re doing it for yourself, too.
这亦是你自己的前路
Wind Waker will make a comeback
召风师今日尚未得手
after today’s failure.
他们势必会卷土重来
Wizards like him
这些江湖异士
are the strongest
原是每月的朔日
on the first day of every month
借助天地之气
with energy from heaven and earth.
焕发出最大的力量
They’ll definitely
他们肯定不会错失
make the most of it.
这次的机会
So you and I will guard Jincheng Palace
下个月的朔日
on the first day of next month.
你我轮值金城宫
Master,
师父
Haishi
海市
trusts you.
对您有所期待
If you keep him in the dark,
此事您若瞒她
something unexpected
倘若他日
might happen
事生转折
and he’ll feel betrayed.
她会伤心的
That’s not your concern
这不是此时
for the time being.
你该放在心上的事
You two should spend more time together
这几日你们两兄妹
before you leave.
再好好叙叙吧
It won’t be easy
将来要见面
to see each other again.
倒是不容易了
Wait.
等一下
I knew you’d be here.
我就知道你在这儿
Look,
你看
the night view of Tianqi
这天启城的夜色
is splendid.
确实壮丽至极
The 2,000-year-old capital on the East Land
东陆两千年的都城
has witnessed dynasties rise and fall
一代代王朝的废立
to get hold of this scenery.
都为了争夺它
What’s gotten into you?
你这个人
Is that some kind of lament?
怎么还感叹上了
Nothing.
没什么
Just the aftereffect
近日宫中事多
of the pressure from work
再加上陛下遇刺
and the assassination.
我有感而发
With all those things
近日都中的事
going on in the capital,
确实挺多的
and Master’s slow recovery,
师父的身体还没痊愈
we can’t take any break.
真是一刻也不能懈怠
I wonder if Master
师父的身体
is going to make a full recovery.
什么时候能恢复啊
He spitted blood again
之前在蝶泉谷
at Diequan Valley.
又突然吐血了
Really?
师父吐血了
Yes. You didn’t know?
是啊 你不知道吗
It happened
就那一日
when His Majesty was attacked.
陛下遇刺的时候
He didn’t say a word about it to me.
他从未跟我提起过
I’m deeply worried about his condition.
他的身体真令人担忧
Actually, I’m anxious these days.
我最近总是忧心忡忡的
Aren’t we all
霁风馆的人
as members of Jifeng Pavilion?
不都是如此吗
Master gets wounded
旧伤未愈
again and again.
又添新伤
He’s working long hours
师父这些日子事多
without eating and sleeping properly.
再加上他宵衣旰食
His body might’ve reached the limit
可能在蝶泉谷
at Diequan Valley.
忧劳过度所至
Haishi.
海市
Take good care of him.
你一定好好照顾师父
What’s going on?
你为何
That doesn’t
突然嘱咐我
sound like you.
好好照顾师父
I got it!
我知道了
You’re hiding something from me.
你肯定有什么事瞒着我
Are you going
是不是给你安排了
to go on an extremely dangerous mission?
十分凶险的任务
No!
怎么会呢
Don’t forget
你可别忘了
I’m the most skilled
你哥哥我可是霁风馆
in Jifeng Pavilion.
第一能干的人
I’ll let you in on another secret.
我再告诉你一个秘密啊
I can
我呢
outlive
比那千年的王八
the oldest
万年的龟
living tortoise.
命都长
Alright. Enough about me.
好了 不说这些了
Just be careful, Fang Zhuoying.
你好好的啊 方卓英
I’m waiting
我还等着
to attend you and Zheliu’s wedding.
喝你跟柘榴的喜酒呢
His Majesty is unwell.
陛下龙体抱恙
Morning court is canceled.
今日免朝
Adjourned.
退朝
His Majesty is always in good shape.
陛下向来身体康健
How did he...?
这次怎么会
Keep it down.
小点声
Can’t you see
没看外面
all those Imperial Guards outside?
多了那么多中卫军吗
- Let’s go. - Come on.
走走走
- Let’s get out of here. - Just go.
快 快走
Let’s go.
赶紧走
Lord Qinghai.
清海公
Your Highness.
殿下
how did His Majesty
陛下怎么突然就
fall ill all of a sudden?
龙体抱恙了
I didn’t know until today
臣今日才知道
that His Majesty caught a cold by accident
陛下去了蝶泉谷泡温泉
after bathing in the hot spring at Diequan Valley.
不小心受了风寒
Then
那
may I go to Jincheng Palace
我前往金城宫探望
to check on him?
可合适
You’re His Majesty’s brother.
殿下乃陛下的亲弟弟
Of course you can.
有何不可
But cold is contagious
只不过据臣所知
as far as I know.
风寒是会过人的
You’ve just
还有
recovered from your wound.
殿下的伤才刚刚好
Thank you for your concern.
多谢清海公挂怀
I’ll go some other day.
那我便改日前往